SRITHARAN BRAVEENAN

+94 77 226 7008 \diamond 32, 8/5, Madhangahawattalane ,Colombo-06, Sri Lanka Mail \diamond LinkedIn \diamond Website \diamond GitHub

OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic and energetic individual with problem-solving and critical-thinking skills, committed team member with excellent communication skills, and leadership qualities. Conducted academic research in the fields of Signal Processing, Autonomous Systems, and Machine Learning. Gained professional experience in Digital System Design, Machine Learning, and Software Development.

WORK HISTORY

Lecturer (Contract) University of Moratuwa	August 2024 - Now
Teaching Assistant (Part time) University of Moratuwa	September 2022 - July 2024
Research Assistant University of Moratuwa	May 2022 - July 2024
Software Engineer Axiata Digital Labs (Pvt) Ltd	July 2021 - May 2022
Software Engineer Intern Paraqum Technologies (Pvt) Ltd	August 2019 - December 2019
Software Engineer Intern Wave Computing (Pvt) Ltd	June 2019 - August 2019

EDUCATION

M.Sc.(Major component Research), University of Moratuwa

August 2022 - August 2024

Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering

Thesis title - Unified Voice Embedding for Speaker and Speech Recognition using Deep Learning

B.Sc.(Hons)Engineering, University of Moratuwa

October 2016 - July 2021

Specialized in Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering

Second Class Upper Division

GPA: 3.56

Dean's List in Semester 1, Semester 7 and Semester 8

HONORS & AWARDS

• Mahapola Higher Education Merit Scholarship granted by the Government of Sri Lanka	2016 - 2021
• Silver Medalist in Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad	2015
• Credit pass in Australian National Chemistry Quiz Senior Division	2014
• Merit pass in Australian National Chemistry Quiz Junior Division	2012
• Merit pass (Ranked 16) in Sri Lankan Mathematics Junior Challenge Competition	2011

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Python	MATLAB,	Verilog	C++	Java	SQL
Languages	r y onon,	, MALLAD,	vernog,	\circ τ τ ,	Java,	യപ

Tools Git, Linux

PROJECTS

Project 1 Real-Time Light Field Video Compression using 5-D Approximate Discrete Cosine Transform

2020

Objective is to develop a real-time Light Field Video (LFV) Compression system for efficient transmission and storage purposes.

Objective is to build an inventory management system with an autonomous quad-copter that minimizes cost and makes inventorying task of warehouses more efficient.

Project 3 Unified Voice Model

On going

Objective is to develop a unified model for Speaker, Speech and Emotion Recognition using Multi-task Learning and create a unified embedding which can differentiate and explain speaker, speech and emotion related features.

OTHER PROJECTS

• COVID19 symptoms detector – Community project	2020
\bullet Custom processor design and implementation to down sample an image - Semester project	2019
• IoT oil lamp – Community project	2018

PUBLICATION

Publication 1 Advancements in Speech Representation: From Feature Engineering to Self-Supervised Learning

Extended abstract accepted in the 28th Technological Advances in Science, Medicine, and Engineering (TASME), 2024.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

\bullet Resource person - Workshop on Sequence-to-Sequence Models in Deep Learning at MERCon 2023	2023
• Resource person - Workshop on Light Field Processing Using Low-Complexity Signal Processing Alg Deep Learning at IEEE EMBS International Student Conference 2021	gorithms and 2021
\bullet Web Master - IEEE Communications Society Student Branch Chapter of University of Moratuwa	2020 - 2021
• Student Coordinator - Tamil Literary Association, University Of Moratuwa	2020 - 2021
\bullet Editor - IEEE Communications Society Student Branch Chapter of University of Moratuwa	2019 - 2020
• Team leader - Archiventure 1.0, AIESEC Colombo South	2018
\bullet Resource person - Robotic workshop for school children organized by Electronic Club of UOM	2018
• Student Representative - Dept. of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering, UOM	2017 - 2018

REFERENCES

Dr. Uthayasanker Thayasivam

Head of the Department and Senior Lecturer, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Moratuwa,

Sri Lanka

Email: rtuthaya@cse.mrt.ac.lk

Prof. Rohan Munasinghe

Professor,

Department of Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering,

University of Moratuwa,

Sri Lanka

Email: rohan@uom.lk

Dr. Chamira U. S. Edussooriya

Senior Lecturer,

Department of Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering,

University of Moratuwa,

Sri Lanka

Email : chamira@uom.lk